Guide to the Stirewalt Family Papers, 1830s-1993
Stirewalt Family papers 1830s-1993
- Martin Luther Stirewalt Papers (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, (7 folders)
    - Between God and Man, by Andrew George Voigt, 1926, (1 folder)
      Annotated by M.L. Stirewalt.
    - Chicago Lutheran Seminary, 1905-1929, (1 folder)
      10 copies of the Record, an annual publication of the Chicago Lutheran Seminary. Includes information about members of the seminary and courses offered at the seminary.
    - Chicago Lutheran Seminary,1906, (1 folder)
      Photograph of the Class of1906.
    - Clippings, 1912-1941,and undated, (1 folder)
      Miscellaneous clippings. Includes: copies of several published versions of sermons and addresses delivered by M.L. Stirewalt; clippings of short articles about M.L Stirewalt; and a single copy of The Lutheran (April 30,1925) with a obituary of Dr. John Edwin Whittiker written by Stirewalt.
    - Colburn Academy, 1906-1918, (1 folder)
      11 copies of the catalogue of the Colburn Academy, a Lutheran School in Mulberry, Indiana. The school changed its name to the Weidner Institute in1911.
    - Legal Records,1943, (1 folder)
      Land sale agreement between M.L. Stirewalt and A.L. Gray.
    - Lutheran Theological Southern Seminary, 1941-1942, (1 folder)
      Board of Trustees meeting minutes for three meetings in1941and1942.
    - Lutheran Theological Southern Seminary, undated, (1 folder)
      2 versions of the organization's constitution and bylaws.
    - Pamphlets, undated, (1 folder)
    - Resume, undated, (1 folder)
    - School Records, 1887-1898, (1 folder)
    - School Records, Lenoir Rhyne College, 1899-1915, (1 folder)
    - School Records, Northwestern University, 1924-1928, (1 folder)
    - School Records, University of Chicago, 1907-1930, (1 folder)
    - School Records, Miscellaneous, 1901-1941,and undated, (1 folder)
    - Syllabus, undated, (1 folder)
      Syllabus and related materials for a series of lectures titled "Four Hunderd Years of the Augsberg Confession."
    - Theological Seminary of the Evangelical Lutheran Church, ca. 1925, (1 folder)
      2 copies of the Seminary's catalog. Includes course descriptions, a history of the seminary and its founders, and description of the school and faculty. A short biography and photo of Martin Luther Stirewalt are on page 20.
- Catherine A. Stirewalt Papers
  The papers of Catherine A. Stirewalt, 1939-1993,the daughter of Martin Luther Stirewalt, are composed of correspondence, clippings, and other miscellaneous papers that primaily document her time spent in China as a missionary for the Lutheran Church.
  - Correspondence, 1939-1991, (14 folders)
    The chronologically arranged Correspondence Subseries consists of letters written by Catherine Stirewalt to her family and friends during her time spent working and studying in China. In her letters she discusses her day to day life in China, the progress of her studies of the Chinese language, and the details of sightseeing trips made near Tsingtao, China. The letters begin in1939,just prior to her departure for China, and continue on a weekly basis through December of1941and the beginning of World War II. Her correspondence resumes after her release from a Japanese concentration camp in1943and continues through her return to China in July of1947and subsequent evacuation from China after the Communists came to power in1949.Her letters from immediately after her1943repatriation include notes written during the difficult five-week sea journey that she made on her return to the United States. The letters from her second stay in China provide a detailed picture of the difficult living conditions for the Chinese people following WWII. She discusses how inflation and scarcity of food and other supplies affected the region of China where she had been working. She also discusses the difficult living conditions of the missionaries and the problems they had performing their work. Her letters in1949discuss the political situation in China, her struggles with making a decision to stay in China, and the day to day lives of the missionaries with whom she is working. There is a gap in correspondence from May of1949until1987when the correspondence series continues with letters Miss Stirewalt received from her friends and former students in China.
  - Clippings, (2 folders)
    The Clippings Subseries includes news clippings of articles relating to Catherine Stirewalt's missionary activities during the1930sand1940sand copies of two1985articles from the journal East Asia Millions about the Weihsien concentration camp. Also included is a photocopy of the title page and title page verso of Langdon Gilkey's 1966book Shantung Compound: The Story of Men and Women Under Pressure.
  - Miscellaneous Papers, (6 folders)
    The Miscellaneous Papers Subseries includes a copy of Catherine Stirewalt's travel itinerary for her journey to China in1939;two essays by other Lutheran Missionaries in China; a postcard view of St. Paul's Lutheran Church in Tsingtao China; two essays written by Stirewalt while in China; an 11 page memoir of her time spent in China, including her experiences in Weihsien concentration camp, written by Miss Stirewalt in1993;and 15 photographs of a1940cornerstone laying ceremony and of the Tsimo School Compound near Tsingtao.
- Miscellaneous Family Papers, 1960-2002
  - Martin Luther Stirewalt, Jr., Papers, 1960-2002, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    Includes correspondence between M. Luther Stirewalt and his extended family, discussing his New Testament research interests and the donation of the Family Papers to Duke's Rubenstein Library Library. Also includes correspondence between Stirewalt and Eedman's Publishing, which published his book on Paul's letters in 2001.
  - Organ Evangelical Lutheran Church clippings, 1934-2002, (1 folder)
    Historical clippings and ephemera relating to the Stirewalt family and the history of the church.